A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Rockefeller University Press, Audiovisual Material FA954
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Rockefeller University Press, Audiovisual Material
undated
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Rockefeller University
FA954
1 Cubic Feet 22 boxes and/or storage containers.
22 boxes and/or storage containers.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Scope and Contents
Audio visual material consists of tapes, cassettes and film reels.
Conditions Governing Access
Material is open for scholarly research, unless otherwise noted.
RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 551 and I 551-U.
Medical education; Medicine, Preventive; Medical technology; Medical sciences; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Medical research; Life sciences; Biology -- Research; Science -- Study and teaching; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; Rockefeller University
- Master film for "A Special Place" re Rockefeller University, circa 1974; (Paige box) 2 8½" film reels in one metal container (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  [Dates per Cathy Rogers].
  Conditions Governing Access
  RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
- Patrick Haggerty Memorial, Caspary Auditorium, 1980 October 20; 1 7-inch reel, 1 cassette. (Box 1)
- Memorial service for Sam Granick, taped by Merrill W. Chase, 1977 June 15; 1 cassette (Box 1)
- Memorial for Rebecca C. Lancefield (1895-1981): Reflections on Her Contributions. Maclyn McCarty, Stuart D. Elliott, Lewis W. Wannamaker, and Carol J. Baker. Taped by Leonard Greenspan, 1982 March 1; 2 cassettes (Box 1)
- The Darwin Lectures: Second Series. The Theory of Neuronal Group Selection. Three lectures by Gerald M. Edelman, 1983 April 5-6 1983 April 8; 3 cassettes (Box 1)
  Related Materials
  For brochure and reading list hand-out, see Edelman biographical file.
- Memorial for René Dubos, 1982 December 10; 2 cassettes, sides A, B, C (Box 1)
  For copies of talks, see René Dubos papers.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition note
  Received 27 July 1983 from Jean Dubos.
- Remarks at Abby Aldrich Rockefeller portrait ceremony and reception, David Rockefeller, Laurence Rockefeller, and Joshua Lederberg, 1983 October 17; 1 cassette (Box 1)
- "A Symposium on Protein Chemistry in tribute to Stanford Moore" (Box 1)
- untitled
  Received August 1984.
  - The Rockefeller University, Caspary Auditorium, 1983 November 4; 4 cassettes (Box 1)
    See Stanford Moore Papers for program with list of speakers and titles.
  - Isaac Bashevis Singer, "A Writer Speaks to Scientists about Literature and Folklore" RU / NYU Jt. Program in the Humanities, Caspary Auditorium, 1980 December 8; 1 7" reel (Box 1)
  - Robert Rosenblum, "Picasso: One Hundred Years Later, " RU / NYU Joint Program in the Humanities, Caspary Auditorium, 1981 October 27; 1 7" reel (Box 1)
  - Fairfield Osborn Memorial Lecture. Russell W. Peterson, "Protecting and Using our Natural Heritage: 'Let's Stop Insulting Mother Nature!" Caspary Auditorium, 1979 November 12; 1 7" reel (Box 1)
  - Fairfield Osborn Memorial Lecture. Clifton R. Wharton, Jr. "U.S. Universities and International Development", 1972 October 18; 1 7" reel (Box 1)
  - Fairfield Osborn Memorial Lecture. Sir Frank Fraser Darling, "The fertile frontier" Caspary Auditorium, 1971 March 23; 1 7" reel (Box 1)
  - Fairfield Osborn Memorial Lecture. Carl Djerassi, "The Bitter Pill: A Perspective on the Future of Birth Control". Caspary Auditorium, 1983 February 2; 2 cassettes (Box 1)
  - Carl Djerassi. PRN Report (Physicians Radio Network), 1983 February 8; 1 cassette (Box 1)
- untitled
  Received 1985 January 16.
  - Cassette tape: Merrill W. Chase, "The history of immunology" Lecture at New York Hospital-Cornell Medical Center, 1984 October 2 (Box 1)
    Introduced by Dr. Murray Dworetsky. Gift of Farrington Daniels, Jr., MD, MPH, of Division of Dermatology, New York Hospital.
  - Cassette tape: Farrington Daniels, Jr. M.D. Sigma Xi Lecture. Technological hazards to stratospheric ozone, skin cancer, and survival of the biosphere. Caspary, 1977 January 27 (Box 1)
    Gift of Dr. Daniels.
  - Lecture by Dr. Christian deDuve, "Lysosomes in Treatment" at Memorial Hospital, 1974 May; cassette tape (Box 1)
    Received July 1985 from Dr. Farrington Daniels, Jr.
  - 75th Anniversary Symposium for the RU Hospital, 1985 October 17; 2 cassettes tapes (Box 1)
- untitled
  Receied 1982.
  - Tony [Anthony] Campo, [Superintendent of Purchases] conversation with Eric Manterfield, [RU Press Interview?], 1973 January 19; 1 7" reel (Box 1)
  - Purnell Choppin lectures #1 and #2, 1974 January 4; 2 - 7" reels (Box 1)
  - Barney Lupinek, [Superintendent, Building and Grounds] / with Eric Manterfield. RU Press Interview. Part 1 and Part 2, 1974 February 21; 2 - 7" reels (Box 1)
  - WNBC66 RADIO. Voice of the Community. "Meet Rockefeller University" with Dr. Hirsch, [James], Dr. Allfrey, [Vincent G.], Ms. Dickson. Part I and II, 1974 June 30 ([Broadcast date], recorded on June 17); 2 - 7" reels (Box 1)
  - Nobel Prize Press Conference, Dr. Christian deDuve, 1974 October 10; 1 7" reel (Box 1)
  - Dr. Frank Field / NBCTV "Rockefeller University", 1976 February 2; 1 5" reel (Box 1)
  - RU 75th Anniversary Reunion. Historical Plenary Session, Caspary Auditorium. Reel 1, Side 1 and 3. Simon Flexner and the Birth of the Institute. James Thomas Flexner, "A Child's View of the Institute" and Saul Benison, "Flexner: The Evolution of His Scientific Career and the Institute" [Citation from inside of reel], 1976 June 8; 1 7" reel (Box 1)
  - Beth Israel Ceremony / RU Hospital re collaborating program in clinical research and education between the two institutions, 1977 February 10; 2 - 7" reels (Box 1)
    See RU News and Notes 8 (March 1977), p. 1.
- untitled
  Received 1985.
  - RU Council. The Installation of Dr. Joshua Lederberg, Monday 1978 October 16; 1 10½ " Magnetic Sound Recording Tape (Box 2)
  - Channel 13. Bill Moyers Journal "René Dubos", 1980 February 20; 1 cassette #018549 (Box 2)
    Separated Materials
    Removed to R.J. Dubos Papers 450 D851 4/29/1986 by GL.
  - Archives Tape 1. Possibly Dubos, undated; 1 7" magnetic tape (Box 2)
    [note: 1975 December 5. The Scholar's Right to Know vs. the Individual's Right to Privacy. Proceedings of the 1st RAC (Rockefeller Archive Center) conference [Identified by CK 8/1986]].
    Removed To Dubos Papers 450 D851 4/29/86 by GL.
  - DIABETES: A NEW PERSPECTIVE [TV Interview], 1976 June 26; Time: 57:35 minutes 1 Zenith Video Cassette (Box 2)
    Host: Jeanne Nicholson
    Guests: Henry Dolger, M.D., Anthony Cerami, Ph. D., Charles Peterson, M.D., Ellen Richmond, Peter Leitner.
  - Archive Center, Tape 2. Side 1 only., undated; 1 7" reel (Box 2)
    [note: May be Tape 2 of 1975 December 5. The Scholar's Right to Know... Proceedings of the first RAC conference].
- "A Celebration of 40 Years of Bacterial Conjugation. - 35 Years of Bacterial Transduction" at RU, 2 Panasonic Premium Standard Video Cassettes NB-T-120PSD. TAPE I and TAPE II MARKED "ORIGINAL", 1986 May 16 (Box 2)
  Includes:
  Retrospectives: Joshua Lederberg, "Columbia-Yale 1945-46" Norton D. Zinder, "Wisconsin 1951".
  Afterwards: Barbara J. Bachmann, "The Culture Collection" Edward A. Adelberg, "The Science"
  Received 1986 June.
- untitled
  Received 1986 September.
  - Rockefeller University Hospital, 75th Anniversary Symposium, 1985 October 17; 2 cassette tapes (Box 2)
    Tape 1, side A and B.
    Tape 2, side C and D.
    [See also: Paige box 1. 2 cassette tapes re RU Hospital 75th Anniversary Symposium].
  - British Broadcasting Corporation radio program. SCIENCE NOW, 1986 August; 1 cassette tape (Box 2)
    (Radio Excerpt Tape. 12 minute excerpt from B.B.C. Excerpted portion is of Sarah Leibowitz (w/Bruce McEwen Lab) and Elaine Tuomanen (w/ A. Tomasz Lab) [1986 August 29, Barry W. Dress/ Joshua Lederberg citing information re tape].
  - Dr. Sam Silverstein. Mountain Climb Antarctic, Derm, conference, Cornell University Medical College., 1967 June 9; 1 cassette tape (Box 2)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Gift of Dr. Farrington Daniels, Jr., 1986
  - RIMR Board meeting, 1935, 1 cassette tape (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller Hospital Reunion Celebration. 75 Years of Clinical Research, 1986 May 7-8; 2 7" reels (Box 2)
    Includes: Joshua Lederberg, "Welcome from The Rockefeller University", Attallah Kappas, "Welcome from The Rockefeller University Hospital", Vincent P. Dole, "Presentation of Conferring Honorary Doctor of Science to Jacques Genest", Igor Tamm, "Presentation of Conferring Honorary Doctor of Science to Edwin D. Kilbourne", Lewis Thomas, "Clinical Research As Basic Science", David Baltimore, "Has Molecular Medicine Come of Age?", Bengt Borgström, "The Art of Intestinal Intubation and Its Importance for Basic and Clinical Research", David H. Blankenhorn, "Measurement of Atherosclerosis in Living Man: Implications for Prevention and Therapy", Elliot S. Vesell, "Pharmacogenetics: The Individual Factor in Drug Response", Harold S. Ginsberg, "Adenoviruses: Agents of "Polypathogenic" Infections".
  - F. Peter Woodford (Conclusion.) "The Quality of Communication and the Communication of Quality", 1986 May 8; 1 cassette tape (Box 2)
- Tower Productions. "Book Ends - Dr. Abraham Pais", 1986 April 18; Video tape. Short version: 4:53 Long Version 6:52 (Box 2)
  Received 1986 October (Marc Kaplan, Public Information).
- WCBS-TV. "Earl Ubell Reports" - Michael Heidelberqer 60:00, 1987 June 6; Video tape (Box 2)
  Received 1987 April (Judith N. Schwartz, Public Information).
- untitled
  Received 1987 March (Barry W. Dress, V.P. University Relations).
  - The Rockefeller University. "Rockefeller University: A Place to Discover" 13:00, 1987 February 6; Video tape (Box 2)
  - The Rockefeller University. "Media Excerpts", Video tape (Box 2)
    No date or running time given. Collection of TV appearances by RU faculty members
    - Dr. D. Martin Carter, CNN - News from Medicine, 1984 November 8
    - Dr. Robert G. Lahita, WNBC-TV 6 PM News (New York), 1985 April
    - Dr. Karl Anderson, CNN Evening News, 1985 May 19
    - Dr. Dennis Stark, WABC-TV 6PM Eyewitness News (New York), 1985 July 29
    - Dr. Rudoloph Leibel, PBS, 1986 April 17
    - Dr. Jules Hirsch, NBC - Today Show, 1985 October 2
    - Dr. Arleen Auerbach, WOR-TV Straight Talk (New York), 1986 March 5
- untitled
  Received March 1988 (Odi Kloesman, Media Services).
  - Convocation, undated; Audio tape (1/4") (Box 2)
  - "Molecular Changes During Nerv-Muscle Synapes Formation" Dr. Lee S. Rubin, 1984 June 11; Audio tape (1/4") (Box 2)
  - "Neuroethology of Animal Communications" Dr. Carl D. Hopkins, 1984 June 11; Audio tape (1/4") (Box 2)
  - "The Rockefeller University and the Graduate Program"-Morning Plenary Session, June 11, ??; Audio tape (1/4") (Box 2)
    David Rockefeller, Gerald M. Edelman, David Baltimore, Joshua Lederberg.
  - "Cell Biology" Aaron J. Shatkin, undated; Audio tape (1/4") (Box 2)
  - Colloquia - EXPERIMENTAL MEDICINE, 1984 June 11; Audio tapes (4¼") (Box 2)
    Edward Reich - "Phenotypic Properties of Cancer Cells", Carol A. Rouzer - "Arachidonic Acid Metabolism by Macrophages", Bernard F. Mach - "Gene Cloning and Experimental Medicine, Two Examples: DNA Typing for HLA-DR Polymorphism and Towards a Vaccine for Malaria", Barry R. Bloom - "Learning from Leprosy".
  - Colloquia - SCIENCE, VALUES, AND RISK: SCIENTISTS AND PUBLIC POLICY, ca. 1985, Audio tapes (2½") (Box 2)
    - William W. Lowrance - "Scientific Appraisal and Societal Management of Environmental Health Risks" (Side 1)
    - Glena L. Paulson - "Sources and Rates, Changes and Fates: An Overview of Pollution Policy" (Side 2)
    - Elena D. Nightingale - "Communicating Risks: Scientists, Media, and the Public"
  - Not identified, Audio tapes (2¼") (Box 2)
  - Public Lecture: "Heart Attacks - Genes and Cholesterol" by Jan L. Breslow, 1985 October 29; Audio tape 1 reel (Box 2)
  - "To Explore and Dream" RU University Relations, circa 1984; Film (Box 2)
  - Thomas Bender Lecture, 1988; Video Cassette (Box 2)
  - Remarks from David Rockefeller and Torsten Wiesel - (re: resignation of D. Baltimore and appointment of Wiesel as President), 1991 December 3; Audio Cassette (Box 2)
- Vincent Dole interviewed by John B. Zabriskie, 2003 December; Includes: Edit Master DVDCAM; Edit Master VHS; Camera Original DVSCAM(s); Camera Original VHS (2). (Box 2)
  Closed to scholarly research.
- untitled, Each title contains: 1 Duplicate camera original, DVCAM. 1 VHS camera original built-in timecode. 1 VHS camera original. 1 edit master DVCAM. 1 VHS edit master built-in timecode. 1 VHS edit master. (Box 3)
  From Thomas Sakmar.
  - Committee on Trust and Estate Gift Plans, Prostate Canccer Immunotheraphy: Testing a Model Cancer Vaccine, 2002 December 1 (Box 3)
  - Celebration of David Rockefeller's "Memoirs", 2002 October 22 (Box 3)
  - "Women and Science, the Estrogren Question: Science Seeks an Answer", 2002 October 9 (Box 3)
  - 42nd Annual Holiday Lectures on Science, Part I, Genomes and Sequences, 2001 December 27; No edit master copy. (Box 3)
  - 42nd Annual Holiday Lectures on Science, Part II, Molecular Switches and Signaling, 2001 December 27 (Box 3)
  - Rockefeller University Council Winter Meetings
    - "Genomics, Proteomics and the Future of Drug Discovery", 2002 April 3 (Box 3)
    - "The Promise of Stem Cells and Regenerative Medicine", 2003 February 4 (Box 3)
  - Announcement of the Rockefeller University's Ninth President. Richard Risher, Thomas Sakmar, Paul Nurse., 2003 January 24 (Box 3)
  - Rockefeller University Council: "Why Cancer Cells are Immortal and Brain Cells Die to Soon, Insight into Programmed Cell Death", 2003 April 1 (Box 3)
  - Women and Science, "How Children Learn: Language, Hearing and the Brain", 2002 May 9; no edit master copy. (Box 4)
  - Women and Science, "Is Beauty Skin Deep?", 2003 May 8 (Box 4)
  - Women and Science, "Weight Loss, Weight Gain: Genetics and the Body-Brain Connection", 2003 March 13 (Box 4)
  - "Compelled to Create? Artists and Scientists on the Process of Discovery", 2003 April 3; No edit master copy. (Box 4)
  - A Tribute to Thomas Sakamar for his leadership as Acting President, Live Event (Box 4)
  - Rockefeller University Committee on Trust ane Estate Gift Plans Spring Dinner Program, 2003 May 22 (Box 4)
- 15 DVD Edit Masters, DVD edit masters for items in Box 3 and Box 4. (Box 4)
- Untitled, All titles include: VHS. VHS with timecode. DVCAM camera original. (Box 5)
  - Maclyn McCarty Interview with Geoff Montgomery, 1998 June 8 (Box 5)
  - Gunter Biobel Interview with Geoff Montgomery, 1998 June 29 (Box 5)
  - AOA Series: "Leaders in American Medicine". McCarty/Krauss. (Box 5)
  - Maclyn McCarty "Neumococcal Transformation and the Discovery of the Genetic Role of DNA", 2004 May 31 (Box 5)
- Jules Hirsch interviewed by Dr. John Zabriskie, 2005 February 22; includes: DVDCAM edit master and camera original. 3 DVD. (Box 5)
- Richard Krause interviewed by Dr. John Zabriskie, 2006 February 10; Includes: DVCAM edit master and camera original. 3 DVD. (Box 5)
- "Vocalizations of Wild Chimpanzees"., VHS and duplicate DVCAM - NTSC. (Box 6)
- "Aspects of the Behavior of the Sifaka", VHS and duplicate DVCAM - NTSC. (Box 6)
- "Patas Monkeys", VHS and duplicate DVCAM - NTSC. (Box 6)
- "Behavior and Ecology of Vervet Monkeys", VHS and duplicate DVCAM - NTSC. (Box 6)
- "Phagocytosis and Degranulation: Studies on Neutrophil Leucocytes", 2002 September 16; VHS and duplicate. (Box 6)
  - "Phagocytosis and Degranulation: Studies on Neutrophil Leucocytes", 9 inch reel. 14 minutes. (Box 6)
  - Print 1, 10.25 inch reel. (Box 6)
- "Pinocytosis and Granule Formation in Macrophages", 2002 September 16 (Box 6)
  Biographical / Historical
  VHS and duplicate.
  - Print B, 7 inch reel, 7 minutes. (Box 6)
- "Aspects of the Behavior of the Sifaka", 7 inch reels
  - Print 3 (Box 6)
  - Print 9 (Box 6)
- Lemur Film
  - First Answer Print, 7 inch reel. (Box 6)
  - Second Answer Print, 7 inch reel. (Box 6)
- S. Gaka NSL Jure, 5 inch reel. (Box 6)
- "Patas Monkeys" PT1, 10.5 inch reel. (Box 6)
- "Vocalizations of Wild Chimpanzees"., 12 inch reels, unless otherwise noted.
  - No print number, One 12 inch reel; one 13.5 inch reel. (Box 8, Box 7)
  - Print 11 (Box 9)
  - Print 12 (Box 10)
  - Print 13 (Box 11)
  - Print 41, 13.5 inch reel. (Box 12)
- "Behavior and Ecology of Vervet Monkeys", 13.75 inch reels.
  - Print 1 (Box 13)
  - Print 2 (Box 14)
  - Print 4 (Box 15)
  - Print 6 (Box 16)
  - Print 10 (Box 17)
  - Print 11 (Box 18)
  - Print 12 (Box 19)
  - Print 13 (Box 20)
  - Print 30 (Box 21)
  - Print 33 (Box 22)